Guide to the Algernon David Black Papers
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series III: Radio Talks, 1934 -1953
  - 1941
    - October 11: America Next (Box 4-5)
    - October 25: Morale in the Camps (Box 4-5)
    - November 1: John L. Lewis and the Coal Strike (Box 4-5)
    - November 8: The Election --And the Next Four Years (Box 4-5)
    - November 15: Community, Solidarity, and Defense (Box 4-5)
    - November 22: Small Business and Defense (Box 4-5)
    - November 29: The Eleventh Hour (Box 4-5)
    - December 6: Democratic Discipline (Box 4-5)
    - December 13: A Warning! (Box 4-5)
    - December 20: Youth's Challenge (Box 4-5)
    - December 27: Democracy's Defense (Box 4-5)
  - 1942
    - January 3: Democratic Defeat and Victory (Box 4-5)
    - January 10: Victory and the Automobile Industry (Box 4-5)
    - January 17: Henry Ford's Apology (Box 4-5)
    - January 24: Youth Delinquency in This War (Box 4-5)
    - January 31: Beyond Tolerance (Box 4-5)
    - February 7: The New Fascist Line (Box 4-5)
    - February 14: Lincoln and Appeasement (Box 4-5)
    - February 21: Appeasement Within (Box 4-5)
    - February 28: Anti-British Feeling (Box 4-5)
    - March 5: Hitler's Challenge (Box 4-5)
    - March 12: Something New in Youth Education (Box 4-5)
    - March 19: American Disunity (Box 4-5)
    - March 26: The Labor Controversy and the War (Box 4-5)
    - April 2: The Anti-Semitic Line (Box 4-5)
    - April 9: Defeat and Victory (Box 4-5)
    - April 16: John Lovejoy Elliot: A Tribute (Box 4-5)
    - April 23: Freedom of the Press (Box 4-5)
    - April 30: Hitler's and Roosevelt's Speeches (Box 4-5)
    - May 7: A Job for All of Us (Box 4-5)
    - May 14: Congress and Peace (Box 4-5)
    - May 21: Enemy Aliens (Box 4-5)
    - May 28: Child Life the City (Box 4-5)
    - June 4: The Case of Harry Bridges (Box 4-5)
    - June 11: Good News (Box 4-5)
    - June 18: The Education Budget (Box 4-5)
    - June 25: The Poll Tax (Box 4-5)
    - July 2: Henry Ford and War Housing (Box 4-5)
    - July 9: PM and the War Effort (Box 4-5)
    - July 16: The Unconquerable Spirit (Box 4-5)
    - July 23: The Enemy Within --Inflation (Box 4-5)
    - July 30: The Dies Committee on Trial (Box 4-5)
    - September 3: The Youth Assembly and the War (not received) (Box 4-5)
    - September 10: Leader or Dictator (Box 4-5)
    - September 13: Have Americans a Fighting Faith? (WOR) (Box 4-5)
    - September 17: A Second Front (Box 4-5)
    - September 24: Getting Tough (Box 4-5)
    - October 1: Parity (Box 4-5)
    - October 8: A New Venture (Box 4-5)
    - October 15: Drafting the Young (Box 4-5)
    - October 22: Drafting of Labor (Box 4-5)
    - November 5: Between Two Worlds (Box 4-5)
    - November 12: Fit for Peace (Box 4-5)
    - November 19: The Sabotage of Democracy (Box 4-5)
    - November 26: Thankfulness and Citizenship (Box 4-5)
    - December 3: Democratic Advance -- Social Security (Box 4-5)
    - December 10: Opportunity and Free Enterprise (Box 4-5)
    - December 17: Unfitting the Citizens of Tomorrow (Box 4-5)
    - December 24: The Christian Spirit and the Extermination of the Jews (Box 4-5)
    - December 31: New Year Wishes (Box 4-5)
  - 1943
    - January 14: Leon Henderson, Scapegoat (Box 4-5)
    - January 21: The War for Equality (Box 4-5)
    - January 28: The Casablanca Meeting (Box 4-5)
    - February 4: Citizenship Opportunities (Box 4-5)
    - February 6: Our Common Faith (WOR) (Box 4-5)
    - February 11: A Job to Do (Box 4-5)
    - February 18: Labor and Fair Play (Box 4-5)
    - February 25: Gandhi's Fast (Box 4-5)
    - March 4: Americans as Trustees! (Box 4-5)
    - March 11: American Workers’ Morale and Absenteeism (Box 4-5)
    - March 16: re: Harlem (no title) - (WMCA) (Box 4-5)
    - March 18: Food and Farmers (Box 4-5)
    - March 25: A Political Landmark (Box 4-5)
    - April 1: Testing Our Wisdom (Box 4-5)
    - April 8: Making History (Box 4-5)
    - April 15: The Color Line (Box 4-5)
    - April 22: Youth and Security (Box 4-5)
    - April 29: The Coal Crisis (Box 4-5)
    - May 6: Anti-Labor Hysteria (Box 4-5)
    - May 20: America the Good Neighbor (Box 4-5)
    - May 24: Americanism Democracy and Race Justice (WMCA) (Box 4-5)
    - May 27: Democratic Integrity (Box 4-5)
    - June 3: Economic Citizenship (Box 4-5)
    - June 10: Youth Demoralization (Box 4-5)
    - June 17: Responsible Citizenship (Box 4-5)
    - June 24: Social Explosions (Box 4-5)
    - October 17: Democratic Education (Box 4-5)
    - October 24: Freedom's Children or Hitler's (Box 4-5)
    - October 31: International Collaboration (Box 4-5)
    - November 7: The Ballot (Box 4-5)
    - November 14: Food Subsidies (Box 4-5)
    - November 21: Juvenile Delinquency (Box 4-5)
    - November 28: Democratic Disunity (Box 4-5)
    - December 5: The Granary of Democracy (Box 4-5)
    - December 12: The Soldier Vote (Box 4-5)
    - December 19: Democratic Employment (Box 4-5)
    - December 26: Peace on Earth --And War (Box 4-5)
  - 1944
    - January 2: The Attacks on Jews (Box 4-5)
    - January 9: War-Time Strikes (Box 4-5)
    - January 16: America Must Choose (Box 4-5)
    - April 13: This Year of Decision (Box 4-5)
    - April 20: The Fight to Vote (Box 4-5)
    - April 27: Cartels and the Peace (Box 4-5)
    - May 4: Hate as a Political Weapon (Box 4-5)
    - May 11: Challenge to the T.V.A. (Box 4-5)
    - May 18: Japanese-Americans: Fellow Citizens (Box 4-5)
    - May 25: A People's Congress (Box 4-5)
    - June 1: America's Conscience and the Negro (Box 4-5)
    - June 8: A Time of Consecration (Box 4-5)
    - June 15: Blueprint for X-Day (Box 4-5)
    - June 22: The End of Hitler (Box 4-5)
    - June 29: The Choice of a President (Box 4-5)
    - July 6: Independence and Interdependence (Box 4-5)
    - July 13: The De Gaulle Question (Box 4-5)
    - July 20: Henry Wallace (Box 4-5)
    - July 27. A German Revolt --True or "False? (Box 4-5)
    - August 3: The Race Issue in the Coming Election (Box 4-5)
    - August 10: The Controversy Over the Kilgore Bill (Box 4-5)
    - August 17: "Wilson and Soldier Censorship (Box 4-5)
    - August 24: Spiritual Security in Wartime (Box 4-5)
    - August 31: The Challenge to the Schools (Box 4-5)
    - September 7: Labor and the Election (Box 4-5)
    - September 14: Compulsory Military Training (Box 4-5)
    - September 21: The World's Conscience and the Jew (Box 4-5)
    - September 28: An Ethical Approach to Religion (Box 4-5)
    - October 5: Do We Need a World Police Force? (Box 4-5)
    - October 12: The Election's Challenge to the Citizen (Box 4-5)
    - October 19: The Foreign Policy and the Election (Box 4-5)
    - October 26: The Spanish Crisis Congress and the Presidential Election (Box 4-5)
    - November 9: Our Post-Election Duties (Box 4-5)
    - November 16: At the Peace Table (Box 4-5)
    - November 23: A New Thankfulness (Box 4-5)
    - November 30: Health for All the People (Box 4-5)
    - December 7: Racism and the Right to Work (Box 4-5)
    - December 14: Are We Fumbling the Peace? (Box 4-5)
    - December 21: America's Duty in Liberated Countries (Box 4-5)
    - December 28: A Crisis in Morale (Box 4-5)
    - December 29: The Common Ground of Faith ("Your Life Today" series: Blue Network) (Box 4-5)
  - 1945
    - January 4: A Challenge to American Citizenship (Box 4-5)
    - January 25: The Wallace Appointment (Box 4-5)
    - February 1: The Controversy Over the Wallace Appointment (Box 4-5)
    - February 8: Do We Need a Labor Draft? (Box 4-5)
    - February 15: Can We Legislate Against Discrimination? (Box 4-5)
    - February 22: The Fight Against Discrimination (Box 4-5)
    - March 1: The Liberation of the Philippines (Box 4-5)
    - March 8: Universal Military Training (Box 4-5)
    - March 10: What Do Americans Believe? (WOR) (Box 4-5)
    - March 15: Education at the Crossroads (Box 4-5)
    - March 22: Cooperation in the War Effort (Box 4-5)
    - March 29: Is This the Collapse of Nazism? (Box 4-5)
    - April 5: America’s Responsibility for Peace (Box 4-5)
    - April 12: The Death of the President (Box 4-5)
    - April 19: Our New President (Box 4-5)
    - April 26: The Issues at San Francisco (Box 4-5)
    - May 3: The Nazi Surrender (Box 4-5)
    - May 10: Our Relations With Soviet Russia (Box 4-5)
    - May 17: Sabotage at San Francisco (Box 4-5)
    - May 24: The New Fascist Threat (Box 4-5)
    - May 31: Democracy and Racism (Box 4-5)
    - June 7: The Treatment of Germany• (Box 4-5)
    - June 14: The Conflict Over Argentina (Box 4-5)
    - June 21: The General Comes Home (Box 4-5)
    - June 28: The Work of Frances Perkins (Box 4-5)
    - July 5: Is American Independence Enough? (Box 4-5)
    - July 12: Reaction and Political Ethics (Box 4-5)
    - July 19: Harold Ickes --A Controversial Figure (Box 4-5)
    - July 26: The British Elections (Box 4-5)
    - August 2: The Challenge to the Schools (Box 4-5)
    - August 16: The War's End (Box 4-5)
    - August 23: What Is the Ethical Movement (Box 4-5)
    - September 6: The Employment Crisis (Box 4-5)
    - September 13: What Is a War Criminal? (Box 4-5)
    - September 20: Religion in the Post-War Period (Box 4-5)
    - September 27: Post-War Strikes --What Do They Mean? (Box 4-5)
    - October 4: Race Conflict Among Our Youth (Box 4-5)
    - October 11: The Marshall Report (Box 4-5)
    - October 18: Crisis in the Schools (Box 4-5)
    - October 25: The President's Message (Box 4-5)
    - November 1: Ethics in Politics (Box 4-5)
    - November 8: The Labor-Management Conference (Box 4-5)
    - November 15: The Atomic Bomb (Box 4-5)
    - November 22: A Thanksgiving Message (Box 4-5)
    - November 29: Religious Education and Religious Freedom (Box 4-5)
    - December 6: Losing the Peace (Box 4-5)
    - December 13: Our Relations with Franco Spain (Box 4-5)
    - December 20: The Housing Crisis (Box 4-5)
    - December 28: Faith in Our Time (Box 4-5)
  - 1946
    - January 3: President Truman's Message (Box 4-5)
    - January 10: A Challenge to the U..N.O. (Box 4-5)
    - January 17: The G.I. Demonstrations (Box 4-5)
    - January 24: The Labor Crisis (Box 4-5)
    - January 31: Petition to the U.N.O. (Box 4-5)
    - February 7: Policy in Germany (Box 4-5)
    - February 14: Fair and Full Employment (Box 4-5)
    - February 21: Religion in the News (Box 4-5)
    - February 28: The U.N.O. and War (Box 4-5)
    - March 7: Sinews of Peace? (Box 4-5)
    - March 14: A New Citizenship I (Box 4-5)
    - March 21: The U.N.O. --Our Responsibility (Box 4-5)
    - March 28: Encampment for Citizenship (Box 4-5)
    - April 4: The Need for Democratic Orientation (Box 4-5)
    - April 11: The Need for New Leadership (Box 4-5)
    - April 18: The O. P.A. (Box 4-5)
    - April 25: The Re-Birth of Fascism (Box 4-5)
    - May 2: Crisis in Palestine (Box 4-5)
    - May 9: A Threat to Peace (Box 4-5)
    - May 16: The Coal Crisis (Box 4-5)
    - May 23: Housing and the Race Question (Box 4-5)
    - May 30: The Strike Crisis (Box 4-5)
    - June 6: Ethical Issues in the Labor Crisis (Box 4-5)
    - June 13: The Strike Against Price Control (Box 4-5)
    - June 20: The Timone Appointment (Box 4-5)
    - June 27: The Security Council and the Spanish Issue (Box 4-5)
    - July 4: July Fourth Challenge (Box 4-5)
    - July 11: The Drift to War (Box 4-5)
    - July 18: Fascist Racism (Box 4-5)
    - July 25: The Rights of Children --Democratic and Religious (Box 4-5)
    - October 4: Ethics in Our Time (Box 4-5)
    - October 11: The Nuremberg Trials (Box 4-5)
    - October 25: The Challenge to the U.N. Assembly (Box 4-5)
    - November 10: The Elections of '46 (Box 4-5)
    - November 17: The Veto and the Bomb (Box 4-5)
    - November 24: John Lewis and Labor's Crisis (Box 4-5)
    - December 1: The New Anti-Communism (Box 4-5)
    - December 8: The Coal Strike Is Over –BUT (Box 4-5)
    - December 15: Report on Germany (Box 4-5)
    - December 22: Is Our Youth Lawless? (Box 4-5)
  - 1947
    - January 5: The Three Fronts (Box 4-5)
    - January 12: Report on China (Box 4-5)
    - January 19: The Price of Milk (Box 4-5)
    - January 26: The Crisis in Georgia (Box 4-5)
    - February 2: Religious Freedom and the Rights of Children (Box 4-5)
    - February 9: The Issue of Rent Control (Box 4-5)
    - February 16: Our Children's Teachers (Box 4-5)
    - February 23: Free Unions and Free Enterprise (Box 4-5)
    - March 2: The Lilienthal Appointment (Box 4-5)
    - March 9: Palestine in Crisis (Box 4-5)
    - March 16: The German Problem and the President's Speech on the Greek Loan (Box 4-5)
    - March 23: The Lost Individual (Box 4-5)
    - March 30: Is the Enemy Communism? (Box 4-5)
    - April 6: What Price Segregation? (Box 4-5)
    - April 13: Roosevelt’s Heritage to Us (Box 4-5)
    - April 20: The Plight of Youth (Box 4-5)
    - April 27: Man’s Greatest Need: Spiritual Security (Box 4-5)
    - May 4: Palestine: A World Problem (Box 4-5)
    - May 11: Wanted: A Constructive Labor Policy (Box 4-5)
    - May 18: Human Rights and Responsibilities (Box 4-5)
    - May 25: World Famine (Box 4-5)
    - June 1: Quest for a People’s Program (Box 4-5)
    - June 8: Military Training for What? (Box 4-5)
    - June 13: The Strike Against Price Control (Box 4-5)
    - June 15: Hollywood Subversive? (Box 4-5)
    - June 22: The New Intolerance (Box 4-5)
    - June 29: The Ethical Movement (Box 4-5)
    - September 7: America and the Atomic Issue (Box 4-5)
    - September 14: Fire Over Palestine (Box 4-5)
    - September 21: The American Merry-Go-Round (Box 4-5)
    - September 28: The Revival of Hooverism (Box 4-5)
    - October 5: Education for Freedom? (Box 4-5)
    - October 12: War or Peace with Russia? (Box 4-5)
    - October 19: The People’s Government (Box 4-5)
    - October 26: Americanism Under Fire (Box 4-5)
    - November 9: America, Russia and Peace (Box 4-5)
    - November 16: American Aid to Europe (Box 4-5)
    - November 23: An Ethical Faith (Box 4-5)
    - November 30: A Great American (Box 4-5)
    - December 7: United Nations: Success or Failure? (Box 4-5)
    - December 14: Freedom Road (Box 4-5)
    - December 21: A Christmas Message (not received) (Box 4-5)
    - December 28: 1948 A Look Ahead (Box 4-5)
  - 1948
    - January 4: What Is Loyalty? (Box 4-5)
    - January 11: Our Foreign Policy (Box 4-5)
    - January 18: Our Puerto Rican Neighbors and Citizens (Box 4-5)
    - January 25: Bearing False Witness (Box 4-5)
    - February 1: Militarism in a Democracy (Box 4-5)
    - February 8: Anti-Semitism (Box 4-5)
    - February 15: Fruits of Empire (Box 4-5)
    - February 22: The Meaning of Equality (Box 4-5)
    - February 29: Crime: Its Control and Treatment (A.D.B. and Edwin J. Lukas) (Box 4-5)
    - March 7: Lessons From Czechoslovakia (Box 4-5)
    - March 21: Is Peace Possible Now? (Box 4-5)
    - March 28: The Conscience of the World (Box 4-5)
    - April 4: Are Our Children Cheated (A.D.B. and Henry Neumann) (Box 4-5)
    - April 11: Universal Military Training (Box 4-5)
    - April 25: Education for Freedom (Box 4-5)
    - May 2: Security: Democratic and Spiritual (Box 4-5)
    - May 9: A Leaderless People (Box 4-5)
    - May 16: Israel: A New Nation (Box 4-5)
    - May 23: The Labor Conflict (Box 4-5)
    - May 30: Ethical Faith (Box 4-5)
    - June 6: Your Personal Freedom (Box 4-5)
    - June 27: America's Conscience (Box 4-5)
    - September 19: Can We Believe in Man? (Box 4-5)
    - September 26: Do We Want Religion in Our Schools? (Box 4-5)
    - October 3. Do We Want Displaced Persons? (Box 4-5)
    - October 10: Conflict Over Berlin (Box 4-5)
    - October 17: The Destruction of Personal Security (Box 4-5)
    - October 31: Your Voice and Your Vote (Box 4-5)
    - November 7: America's Fear and America's Faith (Box 4-5)
    - November 14: The Birth Control Controversy (Box 4-5)
    - November 21: Checking the Marshall Plan (Box 4-5)
    - November 28: Religion and the Child (Box 4-5)
    - December 5: The American Sense of Fair Play (Box 4-5)
    - December 19: Liberalizing Our Divorce Laws (Box 4-5)
  - 1949
    - January 2: War or Peace: A New Year's Challenge (Box 4-5)
    - January 9: The 8Ist Congress (Box 4-5)
    - January 16: The Annual Wage (Box 4-5)
    - January 23: The Inaugural Address (Box 4-5)
    - January 30: A Divided Medical Profession (Box 4-5)
    - February 6: Our Wasted Resources (Box 4-5)
    - February 13: The Case of Cardinal Mindszenty (Box 4-5)
    - February 27: Brotherhood and Segregation (Box 4-5)
    - February 20: Atlantic Pact: War or Peace? (Box 4-5)
    - February 27: Sanity and Faith (Box 4-5)
  - 1949
    - April 3: Work, Happiness and Peace (Box 4-5)
    - April 17: The Easter Spirit (Box 4-5)
    - April 24: Our Policy in China (Box 4-5)
    - May 1: Peace in the World (Box 4-5)
    - May 8: A Constructive Labor Policy (Box 4-5)
    - May 15: Good News! (Box 4-5)
    - May 22: Ethics and Human Conflict (Box 4-5)
    - June 5: Conscience of the City (Box 4-5)
    - June 12: The Religious Rights of Children (Box 4-5)
    - June 19: Religious Instruction and the Child (Box 4-5)
    - June 26: The Meaning of Ethical Religion (Box 4-5)
    - October 7: The Quest for Faith (Box 4-5)
    - October 14: Displaced Persons (Box 4-5)
    - October 21: John Dewey --Educator (Box 4-5)
    - October 28: New Programs of Hatred (Box 4-5)
    - November 4: The Steel Strike (Box 4-5)
    - November 11: The Atomic Bomb (Box 4-5)
    - November 18: The Conflict of Church and State (Box 4-5)
    - December 2: Towards Democracy in Housing (Box 4-5)
    - December 9: Towards World Government (Box 4-5)
    - December 16: The Welfare State (Box 4-5)
    - December 23: The World 1S Children (Box 4-5)
    - December 30: A Free Man's Faith (Box 4-5)
  - 1950
    - January 6: The Right and Wrong of Mercy Killings (Box 4-5)
    - January 19: The People of the City (Box 4-5)
    - January 26: The Conscience of the City (Box 4-5)
    - February 2: American Initiative Then and Now (Box 4-5)
    - February 9: Brotherhood (Box 4-5)
    - February 16: Do We Want Peace? (Box 4-5)
    - March 2: The British Elections (Box 4-5)
    - March 9: U.N. Deadlock (Box 4-5)
    - March 16: A Fighting Faith in Peacetime (Box 4-5)
    - March 23: Good Housing: A Test of Democracy (Box 4-5)
    - March 30: Education for a Foreign Policy (Box 4-5)
    - April 6: Peace and the Sacredness of Life (Box 4-5)
    - April 13: Civil Rights and Civil Liberties (Box 4-5)
    - All subsequent talks we're part of the "Equal Justice Under Law" series (Box 4-5)
  - 1951
    - November 25: The Forgottenest People (Box 4-5)
    - December 2: Hospitals and Prejudice (Box 4-5)
    - December 9: What Other Nations Think (Box 4-5)
    - December 16: The Right to Eat (Box 4-5)
    - December 23: The Christmas Spirit and Bigotry (Box 4-5)
  - 1952
    - January 6: Race Violations and "States' Rights" (Box 4-5)
    - January 13: Our Children's Prjudices (Box 4-5)
    - January 20: The Rights of American Indians (Box 4-5)
    - January 27: Freedom of Residence (Box 4-5)
    - February 3: (re: Africa) (Box 4-5)
    - February 10: Negro History Week (Box 4-5)
    - February 17: (re: Groveland Case) (Box 4-5)
    - February 24: Prayers in Public Schools (Box 4-5)
    - March 2: Conflict Over Segregated Schools (Box 4-5)
    - March 9: Treatment of Chinese and Immigrants (Box 4-5)
    - March 16: Our Immigration Policy (Box 4-5)
    - March 23: Puerto Rican Neighborhoods (Box 4-5)
    - March 30: A Citizen Training Opportunity (Box 4-5)
    - April 6: The Protection of Children (Box 4-5)
    - April 20: (re: Federal Judge W. Waring) (Box 4-5)
    - April 26: K.K.K. and N.A.A.C.P. (Box 4-5)
    - May 4: American Indian Rights (Box 4-5)
    - May 11: Our Children and Youth (Box 4-5)
    - May 25: Housing Discrimination (Box 4-5)
    - June 1: Where Do the Candidates Stand? (Box 4-5)
    - June 8: Learning to Live Democratically and the Life and Teaching of John Dewey (Box 4-5)
    - June 15: Civil Rights and Civil Liberties (Box 4-5)
    - June 21: Preparing for Citizenship (Box 4-5)
    - December 27: Peace on Earth, Goodwill Toward Men (Box 4-5)
  - 1953
    - January 18: Anti-Semitism (Box 4-5)
    - January 31: Event in Harlem: Displaced New Yorkers (Box 4-5)
    - February 8: The President's Address (Box 4-5)
    - March 11: Housing and Low-Income Minorities, N.Y.C. (Box 4-5)
    - March 15: School Segregation (Box 4-5)
    - March 22: Segregation (with mention of the Encampment for Citizenship) (Box 4-5)
    - March 29: (re: children of migrant workers) (Box 4-5)
    - April 5: Federal Funding and Segregation (Box 4-5)
    - April 12: Fair Employment Practices (Box 4-5)
    - April 19: The Birth of Israel --Fifth Anniversary (Box 4-5)
    - April 26: Indian and Wardship (Box 4-5)
    - May 10: Housing and Civil Rights (Box 4-5)
    - May 17: U.N.E.S.C.O. (Box 4-5)
    - May 24: Encampment for Citizenship (Box 4-5)
    - May 31: Civil Rights (Box 4-5)
- Series IV: Miscellaneous Addresses
  - Late 1930s On the Nature of Liberty (Box 6)
  - 1938 no title (re: France and the future of liberty) (Box 6)
  - March 1938 "What Youth Asks" address to an older audience (Box 6)
  - July 1938 Concerning Fascist Forces and "Democracy in Action" (Box 6)
  - December 25, 1938 Addresses by Dr.Wi1he1m Boerner, Ormsbee W. Robinson, &A.D. Black re: Christmas) (Box 6)
  - ca. 1939 Opening Words Sunday Morning ere: Isolation/Collective Meeting of Ethical Security) Society (Box 6)
  - 1941-42 Men of Little Faith Radio Talk (Box 6)
  - 1941-42 (re: personal isolationism) Radio Talk (Box 6)
  - 1941-42 The Wagner Act and the Republic Steel Case Radio Talk (Box 6)
  - 1941-42 (re: isolationism and interdependence between U.S.A. Radio Talk and Europe) (Box 6)
  - 1941-42 (Question re: World War II) Radio Talk (Box 6)
  - January 4, 1942. Message in Response to President Roosevelt's Call to Religious Organizations to Mark America's Entry into the War (Box 6)
  - June 11, 1944. Invasion: A Time of Consecration (Jerome Nathanson, Dr. V.T. Thayer, Algernon D. Black) Special morning service of N.Y. Ethical Society (Box 6)
  - Spring 1945 (after 4/12) On the Death of F.D.R. (Box 6)
  - April 14, 1945 Memorial Service in Honor of Franklin Delano Roosevelt Special morning service of N.Y. Ethical Society (Box 6)
  - May 8, 1945. V-E Day Services. Special morning service of N.Y. Ethical Society (Box 6)
  - May 16, 1945. V-J Services. Special morning service of N.Y. Ethical Society (Box 6)
  - May 1947. Draft of Declaration on Human Rights and Responsibilities. Policy statement of American Ethical Union. (Box 6)
  - October 13, 1956. An Ethical Philosophy of Life. Lecture given outside of Society. (Box 6)
  - May 18, 1958. Your Life and Your Faith, A Graduation Address Purpose Graduation Address, Ethical Culture Schools (Box 6)
  - September 1962. The Theory and Practice of Effective Community Action / Memo as basis for discussion Prepared for Leaders Seminar of the American Ethical Movement (Box 6)
- Series V: Pamphlets
  - Subseries V.1: Published under auspices of N.Y. Society for Ethical Culture and/or American Ethical Union:
    - A. Ethical Culture Movement/Ethical Culture Society (Box 6)
      - Ethical Faith (Ca. 1950) (Box 6)
      - The Meaning of Ethical Culture (1960) (Box 6)
      - Ethical Culture: A Living Faith for Modern Man (1963) (Box 6)
      - Are We Religious? (ca. 1946) (Box 6)
    - B. Religious and Moral Issues
      - What Men Live By (ca. 1935) (Box 6)
      - Our Godless Age (3/14/43) (Box 6)
      - The Church and Religious Freedom (December 1949) (Box 6)
      - Can Humanism Meet Man’s Spiritual Need? (1959) (Box 6)
      - Our Moral Heritage in a World Without God (Annual Felix Adler Memorial Lecture, April 1964) (Box 6)
    - C. Discrimination and Civil Rights